so my message this morning is is
entitled better beggars better beggars
and we're gonna be taking a look at the
parable of Lazarus and the rich man so I
invite you to pray with me as we open up
God's Word Heavenly Father please speak
to us today Lord give us understanding
give us wisdom draw our hearts after you
forgive us Lord for our slowness Lord
make us into your images our prayer in
Jesus name Amen I invite you to turn me
to the Book of Luke chapter 16 Luke
chapter 16 we will begin reading from
verse 19 Luke chapter 16 verse 19 the
Bible says there was a certain rich man
which feared which was clothed in purple
and fine linen and fared sumptuously
every day and there was a certain beggar
named Lazarus which was laid at his gate
full of sores and desiring to be fed
with the crumbs which fell from the rich
man's table moreover the dogs came and
licked his sores and it came to pass
that the beggar died and was carried by
the Angels into Abraham's bosom the rich
man also died and was buried and in hell
he lift up his eyes being in torments
and see if Abraham afar off
in San lavash
and cool my tongue finger in walls
finger in water
but Abraham said son remember that thou
and thy lifetime received thy good
things and likewise Lazarus evil things
but now he is comforted and thou art
tormented and beside all this between us
and you there is a great gulf fixed so
that they which would pass from hence to
you cannot neither can they pass to us
that would come from thence then he said
I pray thee therefore father that thou
would send him to my father's house for
I have five brethren that he may testify
unto them lest they also come into this
place of torment and Abraham saith unto
him they have Moses and the prophets let
them hear them and he said nay father
Abraham but if one went unto them from
the dead they will repent and he said
unto him if they hear not Moses and the
prophets neither will they be persuaded
though one rose from the dead
it seems backward the the rich man
wearing purple and fine linen ends up in
hell there's something strange about
that you see this is a parable and in
parables there are often many symbols
this rich man is first of all rich well
what is he rich with he's evidently rich
with his heritage with the the gospel
with the the treasures that have been
given to him by God he's wearing purple
and fine linen you you perhaps remember
from the book of Revelation that purple
and fine linen represent the
righteousness of the saints and so
apparently this man seems covered in
righteousness
he calls Abraham father in verse 24
signifying that he is a follower of God
what is one who appears to have the
riches of heaven the garments of royalty
and calling God his father doing in hell
it's confusing moreover you have here
Lazarus who seems to be the exact
opposite he is a beggar it carries the
idea of one cringing it carries the idea
of shame the parable tells us that that
he is laid up at the gate meaning he has
no home he is in abject poverty he
appears to not even be able to stand on
his own the Bible doesn't say he was
standing at the gate it says he was laid
up at the gate
couldn't even stand on his own he is so
helpless that the Bible says the the
dogs licked his sores now if if you had
sores on you and dogs were licking your
sores you would be able to shew those
dogs away so they wouldn't come there
again but this man appears to be so
helpless
he cannot even stop the dogs from
licking his sores
by the way according to Isaiah chapter 1
sores are a symbol of unrighteousness of
sin and so here this man is appearing to
be covered in shame unrighteousness in
sin unable to help himself a beggar poor
homeless and the question we ask is what
is one who appears to have absolutely
nothing one who is considered a shame to
society one who sinned and shortcomings
appear so obvious for all to see
one who is so helpless it has no
strength not even a shoe the dogs away
how does one like this end up in heaven
while the man who appears to be rich
with the blessings of God ends up in
hell the answer
is a profound one it lies in the
identity of Lazarus the answer is very
simple
Lazarus was a beggar
what was he everyone Lazarus was a
beggar
this is what saved Lazarus I have a
question for you what was Lazarus
begging for in the parable what was he
begging for he was begging for crumbs I
mean us here you guys said all the time
he was begging for crumbs he was begging
for crumbs now I want to I want you to
hold your place here because we're gonna
go to another story in the New Testament
it's found in the book of Matthew 15 to
shed light on this concept of begging
for crumbs Matthew 15 Matthew chapter 15
and verse 21 Matthew 15 verse 21 the
Bible says then Jesus went thence and
departed into the coasts of Tyre and sit
and Sidon and behold a woman of Canaan
came out of the same coasts and cried
unto him saying have mercy on me O Lord
thou son of David my daughter is
grievously vexed with a devil but he
answered her not a word and his
disciples came and besought him saying
send her away for she cried after us but
he answered and said I am NOT but sent
unto the lost sheep of the house of
Israel so check it out here is this
woman she's coming to Jesus and she's
asking she's she's pleading for His
mercy for her daughter and Jesus
response saying oh yeah no I'm not sent
to you I'm only sent to Israel now what
would you do if you were in that
situation I mean many of us would
probably think oh how rude and we turn
away but notice what the woman does the
Bible says then came she and worshipped
him saying lord help me she's coming
lord help me what is she doing give me
that word again she is begging but the
answered and said it is not meet to take
the children's bread and cast it to the
dogs oh man
many of us would be in a fight if that
was us what what you just call me I know
you didn't just call me a dog listen
then a she answered verse 27 and she
said truth Lord Wow truth Lord this
pause right there for a moment what is
she saying truth - yeah I'm a dog
well how many of us would be humble you
know how many of us would be meek enough
to respond to that yeah I'm a dog but
but notice what she says she says truth
Lord yet the dogs eat of the one eat of
the what everyone crumbs which fall from
their master's table then jesus answered
and said unto her o woman great is thy
faith be it unto thee even as thou wilt
and her daughter was made whole that
very hour what was the crumb this woman
was begging for she was begging for
Jesus's mercy she was begging for him to
speak her her daughter into wholeness
she was begging for the blessing of God
so we may then equate this crumb that
she received with the spoken word of god
jesus speaking saying your daughter is
healed that was what she was coming for
and she says just give me a crumb and I
will be satisfied therefore while
souris desired the crumbs listen
carefully while Lazarus desired the
crumbs the rich man had an entire table
full of the meal now that makes it even
more mind-blowing is that here this rich
man had a table the Bible said he fared
sumptuously he's got all this stuff on
his table and Lazarus is simply begging
for crumbs how can one be saved on
crumbs while the other is lost on a
feast you see the answer is that the
rich man took for granted what he had he
took for granted what he had how many of
you ever been to a resort an
all-inclusive resort maybe a cruise or
something like that where where all the
food is including you can eat all you
want
or you ever been to a restaurant where
you can eat all you want and you know
what happens is you know the first day
on that at that resort of that cruise
you might be what I get to eat all I
want you're so exciting and then stay on
that cruise or that resort for like four
or five days and what begins to happen
they won't have explained you begin to
get sick of food right because it's
right there at your fingertips and so it
appears that this rich man this symbolic
rich man was was so full of food that he
began to get complacent with the meal
the problem with the rich man is that he
was rich and increased with Goods and
taking for granted the help of God the
rich man ate when he wanted to he took
his riches for granted he had food and
drink the Word of God he had the Word of
God right in his reach he he appeared to
be clothed with purple and fine linen
but we understand that that was simply
self-righteousness
while Lazarus was a beggar
you see beggars are poor you know Jesus
said blessed are the poor in spirit
Lazarus had a totally different
mentality a totally different concept
when it came to this food if he could
just get a crumb notice with me Luke 16
back in Luke 16 and verse 27 when the
rich man is in hell symbolically
speaking it says then he said I pray
thee therefore father that that would
send him to my father's house for I have
five brethren that he may testify unto
them the rich man wants Lazarus to
testify unto on to his living brothers
in other words he wants Lazarus to share
with him his experience of how he was
saved are you with me he wanted Lazarus
to - tell them listen this is what you
need to do this is what you know kind of
mentality you need to have if you want
to enter Heaven and the Bible tells us
or or lets us know in this story that it
was the Word of God that saved Lazarus
but it was the same word of God that
condemned the rich man it was all in how
they approach this you seen deliver the
message of Laodicea the message to
Laodicea today is the same message given
is the same message that we see in this
parable of Lazarus and the rich man it
is it is that we must be careful not to
be like Lazarus rich I'm sorry like the
rich man rich increased with Goods
and thinking that we have need of
nothing many will perish with the Word
of God in their presence while those who
hunger and thirst it after the crumbs
are the ones that will enter Heaven
Ellen White tells us in review and
Herald March 4th 1844 she 1884 she says
this take the Bible and on your knees
plead with God to enlighten your mind
what does that word plead me
Beck if we would study the Bible
diligently and prayerfully every day we
should every day see something beautiful
some beautiful truth in a nuclear and
forcible light do you realize that if we
learned how to beg for the crumbs that
every day we would see the truth in a
clear and beautiful light that we had
not seen before but how many of us
approach the Word of God in that way how
many of us approach the Word of God like
beggars Lord please give me a crumb
today please give me something from your
table you see but lot of God has a table
in heaven amen
God has a table in heaven and that table
is filled with angels food and I can't
wait one day to get to the master's
table he has a feast waiting for us in
heaven
but I want you to notice this if God has
a feast waiting for us in heaven if
there is a table waiting for us in
heaven then then surely crumbs must be
falling from that table
do you realize then that that that the
crumbs I love this how many of you ever
read the Word of God and just the light
man this is good stuff do you know what
do you know what this is this these good
things that we read and eat
they are just crumbs okay now some of
your like what how did you listen to me
please
this stuff is only what we can handle
the Angels must be up in heaven like man
they wait till they get up here wait
till they see the master's table you do
know that that the Bible says that God
rained manna down from heaven and what
was manna they were small pieces of
bread this is my brother he always says
you know what he thinks that when we get
to heaven people is gonna be passing out
all the time you know you'll be walking
by someone's past I'd be like what
happened or they just had another
revelation of Jesus Christ like the
stuff that week that we're eating right
now this word of God that is so rich to
us God is like listen these are just the
crumbs we're gonna be studying the plan
of salvation if you want all eternity
but beloved listen we need to learn how
to beg for the crumbs because our our
our level of bread begging for the
crumbs will determine if we even get to
the master's table and right now many of
us take these crumbs for granted again
sister why tells us he who opens the
scriptures and feeds upon the heavenly
manna becomes a partaker of the divine
nature something happens when we beg for
the word of God when we beg for those
crumbs not before for jesus said now not
live by bread alone but by what every
word that proceeds out of the mouth of
God
we beloved must learn how to beg for the
crumbs and to not take the Word of God
for granted so so there are some very
key lessons that we can learn from
beggars because beloved the point is you
and I need to become better
beggars we're not good beggars okay you
didn't get it we're not good beggars you
see listen listen lessons from a beggar
number one beggars have no pride beggars
have no pride you see beggars realize
their condition you and I need to
realize that we are
for that we are are covered in sores
that we are sick and we are in need of
begging we beggars should have no pride
beggars should realize their need and
beloved the the thing that keeps us from
begging is pride we have too much prior
to beg but God says no I need you to
learn how to beg I need you to learn how
to how to really plead and cry out
listen to this I love this quote
speaking of that woman that said to
Jesus truth Lord listen she yields at
once to the divine influence of Christ
and has implicit faith in his ability to
grant the favor
she asks she big she begs for the crumbs
that fall from the master's table if she
may have the privilege of a dog she is
willing to be regarded as a dog what a
powerful powerful statement she is
willing to have the privilege of being
regarded as a dog
she had no pride the rich man
pride the beggar no pride and when we
learn how to beg for us when we learn
how to plead when we learn how to ask
perseveringly that is when God answers
our prayers we need to become better
because not only do beggars have no
pride beggars are always begging never
thought you say amen to that huh beggars
are always begging why because the
beggar realizes that he doesn't know
where his next meal is coming from
that's why the Bible says that we should
pray every day Lord give us this day our
daily bread in fact when the Bible says
ask you know Jesus talking about the
Lord's Prayer and he says when you pray
ask you know don't ask for these things
ask for these things that word that he
uses ask if you
look it up in the Strong's Concordance
the word actually means beg now we take
the word to mean pray but the definition
of the word is big
so then when Jesus is saying ask and you
shall receive the same word is used it
means
beg so we take the word ask to mean pray
but according to the Bible prayer is
equal to begging I know how many of us
don't get our prayers answered because
we need to become better in fact prayer
meeting is actually beggar meeting
yeah yeah that's our prayer meeting is
it's a gathering together of beggars
good beggars beggars will have no pride
beggars will have no shame and this and
I'm not saying look look look
we can pray around the clock yep
we need to learn how to pray around the
clock we need to learn how to pray not
only just at prayer meeting don't get me
wrong I'm not saying if you don't come
to prayer meeting you're not a good
beggar well what I'm saying is you know
some people can't come to prayer meeting
beg at your house are you with me Beck
learn how to bake and then listen
beggars begging together there's nothing
better nothing better God wants us to
learn how to beg by the way he not only
wants us to learn how to beg for the
crumbs of the word of God the crumbs
also represent his buzzing it represents
prayer we need to learn how in fact do
you know that when the Bible says pray
for those that despitefully use you do
what pray for those that despitefully
use you write so check this up if if
prayer actually means begging the Bible
is telling us beg for those who
despitefully use you beg now I'm not
someone's beg this way lord please
destroy him and we begged real good he's
my enemy but no it's not what a saint
beg for your enemies bed for their
salvation beg for therefore for them to
be in heaven God desires us to be better
beggars
beg for souls God wants us to learn how
to beg what beg for the growth of your
church beg for your prayer meetings
before bed for your church before beg
for souls dead for righteousness
dead for truth begged for peace begged
for the Word of God we need to learn how
to become better beggars beggars are
always begging you know what I believe I
believe symbolically speaking that if
there was a sign on the gates of heaven
they would say only beggars allowed only
beggars enter this place
and according to the parable of Lazarus
and the rich man it is the truth because
Lazarus was a beggar the rich man was
not he had everything at his fingertips
and he became self-righteous he took for
granted the Word of God I have always
wondered why it is that so many people
who grow up in this truth you know about
the saying that's right they grow up in
this truth and they and I'm not saying
this happens all the time but but for a
lot of people who grow up in the truth
there is a risk of taking the meal that
has been the table that is in spread
before us taking it for granted while
people who know what it's like to be
starving for truth for direction and
they come and and they they they come
into the truth and they see the table
and a crumb falls and they're on the
ground for that chrome beloved you don't
have to come from outside of the church
to desire and be blessed by the crumbs
that could fall from the master's table
God desires us to learn how to become a
better beggar in fact in Luke 18 Luke 18
I want you to notice it with me Luke 18
there are three different stories given
in there and we're going to go through
them very quickly but I just want you to
notice them you don't have to read them
Luke 18 verses one to eight is the
parable of the unjust judge and the
widow remember that story and the widow
what did she do she there you go story
complete did the judge ah you know I
don't want to hear for the widow she was
persistent
she kept begging she was a excellent
beggar amen
there's another story right after this
one its verse a verses 9 onward it's the
story of the Pharisee and the tax
collector you remember that story who
both of them pray to God one trade in
self-righteousness the other trade as
though he was a beggar Lord I'm not
worthy of anything please Lord just give
me your mercy he was a better beggar the
third story given here in the same
chapter is the story of the rich young
ruler and what did God caught what did
Jesus call that rich young ruler to do
so all that you have and become poor see
beloved that we take that poor to mean
financially poor but none of it I
believe that there was a greater lesson
there that Jesus when he said blessed
are the poor in spirit we need to learn
how to sell all that we have and become
poor in spirit we need to learn how to
become better beggars and the best
example the the most amazing beggar of
all time was none other than Jesus
Christ himself saint seiya how dare you
called jesus a beggar I didn't call him
a beggar the Bible calls him a beggar
can I show you I want to determine me to
second Corinthians 2nd Corinthians
chapter 8 2nd Corinthians chapter 8 and
I want you to notice with me verse
verse nine sin Corinthians chapter 8
verse 9 for you know the grace of our
Lord Jesus Christ that though he was
rich yet for your sakes he became what
poor that you through his poverty might
be rich the great word totals that is
used for this word poor it actually is
it means beggar let me read it to you
from the Strong's Concordance
it says Tojo's is sometimes translated
beggar because of the helplessness of
the individual begging being the only
means of survival
begging being the only means of survival
do you understand here that the Bible is
telling us that Jesus was not just poor
he was a beggar and begging was his only
means of survival
Jesus was a beggar what do you mean
pastor see him begging in the Garden of
Gethsemane see him begging upon the
cross for his enemies Father forgive
them for they know not what they do he
was begging see him begging are for his
father's presence see him begging for
our souls to be saved
Christ was the ultimate beggar he is our
example the Bible says he humbled
himself and became obedient he spent his
life as a beggar I want you to listen to
this Bible echo February 1 1893 listen
to this quote it says Jesus sought
earnestly for strength from his father
he regarded communication with God more
essential than his daily food he has
given us evidence that in order to
contend successfully with the powers of
darkness and to do the work a lot of to
us to perform we must live in communion
with God our own strength is weakness
but that which God gives will make
everyone who attains it
more than conquerors amen the continued
earnest prayer of faith will bring us
light and strength to withstand the
fierce assault of the enemy the listen
to this the light and strength of one
day will not be sufficient for the
trials and the conflicts of the next
Satan is now constantly changing his
temptations as you did with Christ every
day we may be placed in new positions
and may have to meet new and unexpected
temptations it is as consistent to
expect to be sustained today by food we
ate yesterday as to depend upon present
light and present blessings for
tomorrow's success weak and sinful man
cannot be safe unless God shall daily
manifests his light and impart to him
his strength give us this day our daily
bread but love it that means that every
single solitary day we need to be
begging and we need to beg we need to
learn how to beg better than the day
before we need to learn how to beg
because every day Christ has a special
crumb for us from the master's table
that is designed to protect us and keep
us that day
when Christ was begging in the Garden of
Gethsemane his disciples were sleeping
his disciples were sleeping they should
have known better yet a little sleep yet
a little slumber the Bible says so shall
one's poverty come beloved we need to
learn how to beg like our great example
Jesus babe so I want you to see it who
is this Lazarus in the parable who is
this Lazarus and who was Jesus talking
about listen carefully church you see I
believe that this Lazarus in the parable
was none other than the Lazarus of God
the beggar of God Jesus Christ himself
you see Lazarus was hungry well Jesus
was hungry for his father's presence and
the Word of God as well amen
yeah but not only that Lazarus was
covered in sores you're aware that sores
represents sin and the Bible tells us
that Jesus took upon himself our sins
the Bible says that that he was laid up
at the gate of the rich man's home he
was laid up at the gate of the rich man
home he died outside the gate of the
rich man's home you see beloved when we
look at this problem we begin to
understand that the rich man was a
symbol that Jesus was using of the Jews
who had all these riches from their
heavenly Father and Lazarus the guy that
was the dagger oh yeah who wants to be
like him Lazarus was none other than
Jesus himself who wants to be like you
the Bible says the dogs licked his sores
you remember reading Psalm 22 where
Jesus's Prayer talks about the dogs
surrounding him well listen to this the
Bible says that Lazarus died it says the
rich man also died check this out
the Bible tells us that Lazarus was
taken to the father's bosom do you guys
catch what I just said Lazarus was taken
to the Father father Abraham his bosom
what beloved its strength that just as
Lazarus died
taken to the Father's bosom so Jesus
dies is varied resurrected and then a
sentence to the father's bosom now watch
this the rich man in the parable says if
you would just raise one from the dead
if you would just raise one from the
dead then we would believe my brothers
would believe but the answer comes back
no what do they have they have the table
they have the Word of God they have the
feast if they will not pay attention to
the feast then though one rose from the
dead I got a question did one raise from
the dead
did they believe after he rose from the
dead you see beloved the lesson is this
if we if we take for granted the crumbs
that have been left for us if we take
for granted the the privilege of Prayer
if we take for granted the privilege of
studying the Word of God if we take for
granted the privilege of soul-winning if
we take these things for granted then
just as the Jews were not moved by the
resurrection of Jesus Christ so we too
at the second coming of Christ will not
be prepared for him we church need to
learn how to become better beggars
begging for truth begging for
righteousness begging for souls
begging for unity begging for the
righteousness of Christ to cover us
heaven is for beggars only I invite you
touch to become a better beggar